Leah J. Barnes

Charlotte, NC | 828-308-6083 | johnson.leahe@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/leah-j-barnes-93b06b135 | Portfolio: https://ljbarnes.github.io/Portfolio/ |

GitHub: https://github.com/LJBarnes

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Utilizing past art and design experience to create dynamic websites and applications that are both visually appealing and functional. Developed and refined skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, NodeJS and other current web technologies by completing a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of North Carolina Charlotte. A versatile self-starter with exceptional written and verbal communication able to work individually but also excels at team collaboration. Looking forward to blending creative and technical skills to create a web experience that is both effective and enjoyable.

SKILLS AND PROJECTS

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, APIs, Media Queries, JSON, GIT, GitHub, jQuery, JavaScript, Node.Js, the command line

Secure Password Generator

- Built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Collects user input via prompts
- Generates strong user password based on user submitted criteria
- https://ljbarnes.github.io/password_generator/

Day Planner

- Created with HTML5 and Bootstrap
- Powered by jQuery and Moment JS
- Dynamically updates HTML and saves user input to local storage so schedule persists after page is refreshed.
- Utilizes Moment JS and CSS3 to color code past, present, and future hours of the day for easy readability.
- https://ljbarnes.github.io/day_planner/

FurEver Home

- Lead developer in a group of 3
- Powered by Materialize CSS, ¡Query, The Dog API and The Cat API
- Search functionality based on user input
- HTML updated dynamically
- https://pdorqu00.github.io/FurEverHome/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Photographer, Social Media Manager

Robert Abbey, Inc, Hickory, NC

July 2015 - Present

- Created images for print and web and managed social media posts and platforms for home décor manufacturing company specializing in lighting
- Edited images and created graphics using Adobe Creative Suite
- Reduced media outsourcing by 80% by bringing all photography and social media management in-house.
- Recognized by senior management as a talented employee with the ability to take on multiple roles and provide extremely fast turnaround with projects.

 Selected for proven subject matter expertise to work with e-commerce partners and large format printers, providing them with necessary images and data

Freelance Photographer

Hickory, NC

May 2010 - July 2015

- Worked as a professional photographer and photo editor on a wide range of projects including product photography, family portraits, and professional portraits
- Maintained excellent working relationships with clients
- Edited images using Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Lightroom
- Created content and maintained professional portfolio website

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

University of North Carolina Charlotte, Charlotte, NC October 2019 – April 2020

UNCC Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp – An intensive, fast paced 24-week program designed to establish and cultivate proficiency in web development. Skills learned include: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git, Command Line Node JS, My SQL, MongoDB, & ReactJS.

Appalachian State University, Boone, NC August 2005 – May 2010
BFA Studio Art Photography